<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R | Data science | Visualisation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R | Data science | Visualisation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Learning: Cross Validation wrong and right way</title>
      <link>/2018/01/27/statistical-learning-cross-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/27/statistical-learning-cross-validation/</guid>
      <description>IntroThe Wrong WayThe Right WaysummaryIntroCross validation is one of the most popular methods for estimating test error and selecting tuning parameters, however, one can easily be mislead/confused by it without realising it.
In chapter 5 of An Introduction to Statistical learning, the authors stress that if a dataset has a lot of features and relatively fewer observations, the variable selection process should also be cross validated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Learning: a bootstrap sample contains two thirds of original data points?</title>
      <link>/2018/01/21/statistical-learning-how-to-prove-a-bootstrap-sample-is-expected-to-contain-63-2-two-thirds-of-original-data-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/21/statistical-learning-how-to-prove-a-bootstrap-sample-is-expected-to-contain-63-2-two-thirds-of-original-data-points/</guid>
      <description>IntroRecently, I am studying The Elements of Statistical Learning out of my own interest. An interesting topic they covered briefly on their online videos is bootstrap. Bootstrap, in the simplest terms, is the process of generating samples from sample. Say you collected a sample of n data points, a bootstrap sample is generated by sampling n data points from the original sample you collected with replacement. (So Given a sample size of n, you are able to generate \(n^n\) bootstrap samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R: Setting options</title>
      <link>/2018/01/07/setting-options-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/07/setting-options-in-r/</guid>
      <description>When developing a package or a set of functions, you often needs a lot of options. Often, you would want to set some sensible defaults for each option whilst giving users the flexibility to customize and extend. Take ggplot2 for example, if you ever used it, you know the background of the plots is, by default, grey, though You have the flexibility to change it.
While there are many ways to set options, I haven’t found a summary of pros and cons of different approaches and I certainly don’t know what best practices are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an actuarial analyst working at Taylor Fry, Sydney. I studied actuarial science and statistics at the Australian National University.
Inspired by Yihui, I realize I should try to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m learning - it could be an effective way to turn passive learning into active/creative thinking and consolidate my thoughts. I also hope my posts can help others as well as helping me. And I wish to connect with people who share similar passions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>/2018/01/01/my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/01/my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>If you’re not prepared to be wrong, you’ll never come up with anything original.
— Ken Robinson in a Ted Talk
Starting this blog as new year resolution!
While building this blogdown website is made so easy with blogdown package, I did have a difficult time setting up ssh for use. Perhaps I should learn the ssh and do it as my second post? I also want to talk about R, vim, building websites as I learn it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>